I know you have a beard...that I can tell.
Okay, looks like that clocks taken so.
Revenue...hope you guys are enjoying gels...join build
...twenty fifteen.
My name is mike morton I'm a program manager on the asher tools team a
were team inside
a visual studio we work on the sdk in some other things and we'll walk through today
...to do kind of it's a two-hour level session because...kind of a high-level of what's new I'll be
honest if you went to the five perfect sessions you've probably seen everything I'm going
to show you today but chances are you have assume all sold likely they'll be a duplicated
to hopefully I'll show you something new that may be keynote kind of brushed over something so I
I'm pretty sure you walk...here learn a couple things.
If nothing else will probably have a couple
laughs something go wrong or make a joker you guys make a joke so stick around what...
whatever that's new slide all right so as you sdk what is the measures
...what are design goals why do we build is really about
focusing on the cloud and the web developer scenarios we...to make tools to make it easier
for you alta to build...applications take advantage of
...the best you can very customer driven so please give us feedback every
day any day heavily here to go up to our feedback site we ship
...tools often typically as you probably know about every four months so sometimes it's
three-month server three to four months worship...a new address
...as you probably heard the address decay to sixes available just
yesterday I believe we provide side-by-side so if you're...not to or
...to dot five we do support side-by-side so not everyone knows that you don't half-done install the
old one reinstall new you run the side-by-side as needed and typically we
support the current version visual studio...one version back we're kind of
an odd state because we have this new version the visual studio twenty fifteen rc that was
just-released and we do have an sdk that support on that version also so
right now we have three different ones free to choose from if you went up to the as your arms
...the web platform installer you would see that you can install one of those three so it's available today
gone up to the web platform installer install the one that matches the visual studio version your running?
...how many people are...to dot sexual...everybody install to...section I
see like a handful what are people running a quick show hands to dot five
whose one-to-five...five okay and older into out five...pick on you to...or
...anybody on the one-dot still.
Good answer good answer...as, you know,
we do have a support lifecycle so keep an eye on that we support quite
a few but I'll be honest we're trying to tighten up a little bit so don't get too far behind.
All right.
I have maybe half doesn't maybe eight slides...to go through the first three of
...jump in the demos and I'll probably just
...unless you guys have a problem with it probably just go through all my demos and if we have time or jump
back and we can recap on a couple slides if we have time but I think everybody would rather see product
bits than slides lot-of nods okay so today will go over six or seven things.
Real quick like two-minute thing on app service and
...get into details we'll talk about connect services diagnostics and you can read the rest of those
...let's just get onto the...
You...go there we go so first is the as
...service...actually announced a few weeks ago maybe three or four weeks agowe actually
had an sdk that was the to top five dot one release
...to five-one couple people okay so...you guys played with app service all
...to six has some improvements on the app service again I won't go into a lot of details because
there's a number of sessions here I have some links...decked...sessions one that's already gone
and one that's tomorrow I think this is an area that I'm deep...I'll just be honest but it's pretty cool they're
offering this integrated a new offering basically...things that were app sites
before now for websites...web apps what we also have mobile apps and api
...and these new things called logic and, the top three the web
apps mobile apps logic caps the kind of all build on those api apps so definitely something
...check out what allows you to scale all these together I think actually it's going to save
you some money if you're using the miscellaneous pieces today like websites
and mobile services bringing these together actually gives you some consolidated
savings excusing they've also...with the with the logic
gaps there's really cool connectors to a lot of the sas of systems that you may user your customers
menus the logic...pretty need if you haven't seen as a great demo you go
...to the portal you can drag-and-drop these like many blades under there and configure
...pretty awesome think about like a workflow that's up in the cloud so,
check those out that's about all the detail go into...
Connected services so this is something we
redid connected services in visual studio twenty fifteen we actually released in the preview back
in the fall and we have a few updates to at the main update is we added
app insights as a service that you can add...services does is
say have a web app or any type of app and you want to leverage one of your as
you resources this makes it really easy to just point out...resource who will bring down the configuration
and help configured for you ...the new get package that you may need to use that the storage,
for example, so, this is really easy really helps get you started quickly the
...leverage your services in your application one of the thing that we are offering now is we have
an sdk so-if folks and here have their own service that maybe...an upon
...but somewhere else...for sales force has a connector that they've put into connected services
other people have a service that...like to bring in...sdk that you all can leverage
and get your own paper resources into the into the visual studio...services experience.
And, then diagnostics will goal we'll going a little depth here we have some nice
changes here that I think people are really really like...as,
you know, diagnosing
your cloud apps in your eyes apps one-third deployed.
It's a challenge you can't just...the...and see what's going on
...creative...in using logs is critical and...the windows...
diagnostics which is what makes that fairly easy to do so we now support diagnostics when you
f five and emulator so you can trialed all of your all
...your...sources in your trace right events and stuff that you're doing in the
past well-supported so that's a really nice thing I'll show you how that works.
And, you know, longer have to try to reader logs that little small window inside
...visual studio you-can out easily export those out to
...a...file and warm-up in excel or already whether viewer that you want
that handles a seos vs and then we improve the viewer a little bit and I'll show you what that looks like.
All right let's jump into a demo here.
All right so here we are in
matching a flip back and forth this is visual studio twenty thirty or do a
demo couple demos and each just to show you or sdk for the most part
...supports the both things the both the versions just as well there are few new things towards the end
I'll show you that are only supported...twenty fifteen so all point those out when we get to?
All right so first here we have an application this is the can
...so ads application you up to agile dot
com download that it's a good learning application it's got a worker...a web role.
The web role rights to database you basically you'll you are you can put in put
an ad in a picture of...gets into the database the picture gets written
to blob storage and then we actually write a small q message just a wake-up the worker role
...the work role grabs that turns into a thumbnail so pretty typical application but
let's...experiment with both the worker...the web roles people using worker web roles quite a bit.
So, for those of you that are not are you guys all do and ios.
So, if you do need is anyone doing something other than I as or web and
...such as just websites just websites so few okay it's good to get
a feel for this so this is applicable to paths or your worker
web roles as well as I as for the most part it's not the same for websites,
websites has a little bit different diagnostic story so this will make sure we set that context good.
So, I...I have a application that I described to you and we want we want to make sure that we put out
events both in the web and the work rules so we could figure out what's going well what's going on not so well
so what I've done here is here's the web roles configuration one thing that
we've brought back we've made it easy for
you appears where you can you can pick
your different configurations however local configuration and you'll see here that now I can use my local
deb storage that...the emulator all my event logs what windows
as a diagnostics is going to pump those out to my local...storage
...I'm in my cloud configuration you'll see them point-two a real storage account that's up
in manager so that's a nice little thing that we had and then the configuration applies the both
...you...the configure...this is we can set up your configuration for windows
...diagnostics this isn't necessarily
new just one...point out so everyone knows that you can come here and you can turn on...period
the how often you want to transfer storage from the local storage
on the gm into the table storage up and as your you can also...the
log level here and you can do that for your application logs your windows event
logs such as your system application whatever...you want you also
different perf connors and we turn on a few by default but you also turn on whatever perf
...you want as well as create your own so is this all familiar to people there's
They yell out faster of this is all just duplicateyou
also do your infrastructure logs so these are the logs were casual is actually write messages for things
words maybe scale and upper scaling down transfer any kind of log uone as well as
you gw and we have our crash dumps so if you're trying to fire up a web or work role you
have a crash this is where you can say hey any crash for these
kind of processes automatically copy those into my ...table storage so you can
analyzers so I've got inset these as you can see the main we'll focus on is application log.
And, the events that were going to be getting our
events such as this so here you can see let's go to the web here's
the web role here's a web role so this is when I get a new add-in.
Excuse me you can see that were rightnow different messages so when we write some
...to database there who can see that were doing that when we create a
...message so on so forth just events that we can get that tracing information so
if something goes wrong middle-of-the-night...look at...logs and have a good idea at least maybe not
exactly why but at least kind of where the issue is that you can zoom into that area and
then similar on the worker role as...q we're writing messages out
saying hey we're here we didn't find the message you can't creative thumbnailwhen it successful
generator thumbnail so on so forth so we just use these real simple trace events to
...these logs so I can really know what's going on with my work on web...
So,...let's...five that.
So, this is going to use our local emulator.
Does it go in these services configured file it's going to go into
...I'm experience...here hang...
We have a web configure xfiles that's hanging off of each...you meant, yeah.
All right the demo.
Beast.
Has gotten me?
...think that eventually going to finish but we're going to...rhythmic that happen a little faster.
So, that are just you can see
realtime diagnostics here so when this happens just.
That uses way for me to make sure it doesn't happen the second times...going to shut down the emulator so just shut down
...local emulator and all restart visual studio here.
All right so restart visual studio and we will neatly just f five that again.
Open that project back-up.
All right let's see if we have a little better luck here.
So,...five that was good luck with a little flash the diagnostics that's basically
...the diagnostics on the local emulator so now we start the
emulator up from scratch this take a couple more minutes I was I was a good demo and I
pre warmed all this stuff for us but then I had to shut down via so it's kind of
...do over so here we...website this...web role again it's a simple
ads is like maybe if you have ads for your internal companies nothing fancy is not
replace craig's list necessarily and we can see let's just go ahead and create...
We're going to start this up right so let's have a jeep that I wouldn't mind so on?
For a decent price.
I don't really want to sell...my wife wants me...so.
We'll go ahead and pick that will like that and we'll make this quick since we have to...stuff and only get
...for behind so we're going to go ahead and add that g pad that's going to create the database record with some
of information it's going to put the full-size image
into blob storage and then write a really short just q message will trigger the worker
role and if I refresh here's my jeep that I just data down here if I refresh we should
see the there's the there's the sm imagery the thumbnail of course we can edit that and
changes if we wanted to all right let's adamant add one more?
So, that's also it's also get rid of my chopper.
...does not likeit.
Probably not a great description but.
Go ahead and sell that too...will create that so now we've got a couple records there and we should
see that refresh so there are...roles grabbing that q message going to the blob and generating
...the message so we're going to shut this down
if you remember we had our configuration...we...doing those trace events so those trace
events they all go to a storage q over here I'm sorry table actually.
...for how many people are using the asher node and server explore the look at various things.
Really the rescue dot one of the rest...use...use.
No.
Right.
Everyone know about the...storage and...and websites and stuff okay so,
I can go here and I can look at my storage in the first one is always your development storage
and if you look...the tables you actually see a set of tables that are fairly obvious here's
...infrastructure log scope visuals performance counters in your different event logs
go there's a couple that actually go straight to blobs which I'm not currently
outputting but most of them come right...your tables and this web logs table that's the one that
...your main activity logs are going to come to and the best way
I've found is to go and sort by precise terms...excuse me.
And, we'll get our latest one up here and then we can go over here and you want to
look at the message column that's where the actual messes that you write out is going to go.
And, this is going to usually take.
So, there we got some uploaded files this usually takes a minute or two for those logs
...get written to the role which is run on the vm they get written to that store...on the on the
...and then you can set how often if you remember come back up here.
I said for this web role.
I set how often I want that information to be transferred from the local storage into
my table storage and for default we go back here.
I said the default or the setting to be one-minute so every minute I want that
transfered what's about a minute give or take thirty seconds so,
that's why I say it's about a...leg for...information to get into that
table in fact if we refresh that you can do that with this right here.
We probably have a few more that have coming on.
Worded...info so again precise time stamp is
...the most accurate times camp and then go over
and expand that message count that's the easiest way to do that and you can see those messages so you can see
that I've been uploading those images
...earlier I had a few exceptions...so you see those exceptions in
...in fact let's do let's do this so this is during a
five so this is...the emulator now supports writing out to these diagnostic
clogs a great way to test the make sure that your diagnostic
information's been written out correctly but then of course once you're in production
...that cloud service I have this deployed also...
Expand this up.
And, this is my can...so...zero that's my production one
...and launch that so this is the one that's deployed up to asher.
It came up a little behind there so let's go ahead and create...
Upon this version of it and that's
grab and image will grab my will grab a picture of where we have
another jeep picture you can tell I'm...to...add one of these?
We'll put in whatever what...skip this quick so we don't run behind.
The car will...create.
And,...add one more so this one's actually even though it's got to p and g
...this is actually going to be it's actually just a notepad file with
some various characters so actually want
to fielded invalid ones I want to show you what you can look for.
When these don't work so
mingle create new and I'll grab this file here which is not a picture?
...test because we're not going to fail and...to give price
concedes zero because it's in the free category so that one if I hit a five-year few times
going to notice that so there's my jeep picture that I just have put in here so
that one's already been processed but this one you'll notice isn't going to come back.
So, this time rather than go to that local storage what we're...
go to is the way you look at that...close...not confusing close that close
...you do is you go down to the web
...the work role in this case I just know that the work roles the place where we
process that image so we want to do to look at that diagnostic information
you want to go down to your worker role you can go down to an individual...instance
on this case I have one so it doesn't really matter and I say view diagnostics data what we're going to do
...going to pull...down from that live running role and you'll see that I have
an application air and my guess is this is from the one I did a few minutes ago
when I was out just before we started because this again takes a few minutes to come down so I
be surprised if it came down that fast and you'll see actually let's do this.
You'll see we have a new export feature so right here you export to...when we go ahead and do
that we'll save that to my desktop so again you don't have to view...that...
you can go ahead and create a comma separated table or a file?
And, then we'll just go to the desktop and open that up.
We only have one row expectancy more than one-room.
...we only had one so we can look at that excel
we go to the message right here open that up.
And, we can see that we got an exception but it's actually not
...we wanted we would have to let me see if I can go like this.
So, I change...forty five minutes I'm going
...refresh there we go so those are some of the messages I was looking for underscore look at them right here so now the do
it again but you'll notice here in the worker role...we had here is we
are invalid parameter that was sent in as argument one and if you look at the method that
...call-in which are just covered up with my with my
thing their income on there we go you'll see that
we're calling the work role convert image and we're passing the stream so this is because I gave
it invalid method are invalid image to process
...I'm trying to show you here is where to go to look at these diagnostics because again you can't set a
live debug session when you're in production so you need to know a make sure you put not
enough event messages whether...just trace events and then knowing where to come
afterwards to find those event messages so that you...figure out what's going wrong is really important.
Ok,
so, this doesn't scale infinitely obviously if you have a whole bunch of roles here I had
two roles so it's pretty easy so we've actually been working with some open-source
projects elk...anybody using...stack which is elastic search
...stashing the bottom so we actually have some
scripts that we've created that make it really easy to stand-up and elk a and
...stack in as you're either on a single machine autumn on a multi-english
...just depending on how much you need so if you're
doing maybe five or six or more roles you might want to think about a way to process
...that the log information and be able to look
at across all of those logs because the going-to each one look for messages just doesn't
scale very well so here's what one of those dashboards looks like.
...refresh this so this is live against that this site that's been published to
asher so you can see here that I'm looking at different things so we have
a chart for available memory so we'll see how
the memories available in this case I'm the only users so there's not a lot going on
with recur cpu and we look at different stuff and you can you can customize these
cabana dashboards however you want so basically what's happening here is we're
taking that data out of as your storage...using logs...
into elastic search and we've built this dashboard and capone to look at certain kinds
of logs that we care about such as the
...logs so right now I'm looking at today is if I was
...soon all right and then.
I can actually pick the...here we had five
errors so one is zoom into their...
Among and.
You'll see how it just went down
resume those for errors and you can see the time period up here in the top right that we just
zoomed into well we didn't just zoom in on that one...chart
...this whole dashboard so you actually see that resume there were only...messages that
occurred during that time and we can keep...as far as we need to you can go up and you can look at
the bigger periods of one look at...all the things are going wrong this
...this month you've customize these...dashboards.
Immensely this is a real simplified one compared
the things we've seen so if you're if you're using a lot of roles or a
...I svm this is something you might want to look at login
we have the scripts that will help you set this up and all have a...those later in the presentation.
All right.
Let's.
Go back to...slides real quick.
Diagnostics so any.
Any questions that are just big and...don't want to wait for that might get lost...answer no...
...add alerts socapone does have a way to
in alerts does the as your the average measure infrastructure has alerts also that you can set
up so just depends on where you want to set those I don't know if that's part of the free
cabana it's not a product that microsoft's also...going to comment on that?
But, the answer is yes one way or another you definitely can.
Ok, the switch gears
...hereas your rm so there's been a few talks talking about the new as
you resource manager when you when I say as a resource manager
...of think new portal people using the new portal ok,
some are people familiar with as...resource manager vs kind...the old
...people understand the difference there not exactly okay I'll show you some of the
tooling bottom line is as we move to the new portal the resources that were used to seen
...old portal those are kind of moving over if you've noticed the
new type resources like data factory and the...cash?
And, mice sequel I believe those you can only go create on the new portal you'll
see more and more of that as we go so getting familiar with the new portal and,
this new as your rm stack is going to be pretty important...as definitely the direction that measures movies.
We have some tools that we've created a which gives you a bunch of starting point
template like a vm or website with a database we
have a number of starting points but we have a number of
don't home snippets because it's not like right click insert snippet...a number of that's called
sub templates that you can add to those starting point templates and we have tools that
help you navigate this big json file but what's great is json file once
you describe all of the resources that you want vm with a virtual network with
a database it's great because it's easy to repeat you can spin up attest version chutzpah
...version or as many other maybe intermediary versions that you need.
Actually...
...just one slider one of the thing that we've done is we've
modify the deployment process in this in this as your resource manager tooling I'm...to
show you that actually uses our shell so if you want we have a great powerful editing experience
now in visual studio twenty twelve and twenty or twenty thirteen and twenty fifteen.
you can edit that our show however you want so that when you publish whether it's direct
through the our shell or even using our deployment dialogue it's going to execute that same our
shall...customize that take advantage of it and I'll show you how to do that right now.
...don't...that you will need this problem?
Right so let's close this project.
It didn't switch I'll hit it again thank you.
...go...lucky thank you.
Right close this out let's start a new project here so what do is start a new
project and you'll notice actually in the st ktwo five
we actually released this the starting point of this functionality at that point it was called
...cloud deployment project...use a cloud...project.
Ok, so, we got one couple people we might want to talk afterwards
...a little manual migration you may need to do
...going forward these as a resource group project same exact concept...just done some renaming and,
some adjustments but,...much better
position I think and create one of those so this is something again you're going to
define your resources so you may are not may or may not do this and the same solution we
are have your code I actually like to...to have my coda...configure together and get it all in
the source control together I think it's a really good practice but everyone has their own preference
there but you see here I have a number of starting points if I just want
...simple web app well that's why we could do that but if I want something a little more
little more tough to describe is a new virtual machine this is actually use the
new vtwo virtual machines that just came out...couple days.
So, let's go ahead and pick that let's say have an application that I want to run
...virtual machine but I also want to use as your sequel
...describe that environment so I can spin up and take it down as much as I
...a one so we'll pick that we'll say ok this is going to create one of those as your resource group projects.
And, those are nice entirely...you'll see here we have scripts and template so
the main things if we look at the templates...that will bigger.
You'll see that we have a virtual machine json template so this is the resource template who
...mcdowell bigger.
So, you'll see that the templates made up of three main sections you have parameters you
can have variables and you have resources with resources...kind of the star the show but
parameters and variables are very important because what they allow you to do is described those resources
once and then have a parameter file which we give you one which is called parameter...dev
...many of these parameter files uone for devon for test integration production whatever you need?
So, let's take a look at this file
here also notice we gave you a nice json outline view over here so
for expand this you can see in the resources as a storage account you'll see how
...a click on one we highlight the other one so it's real nice that you can stay in
...here we also generate a public ip address virtual network,
network interface card...course the vm itself so again these are
those new vtwo vehemence they give you a lot more flexibility...our so,
definitely take a look at these kind of a new stack for vm zing compute resources
...storage...so let's now go ahead to...resources so we talked about
...a vehemence this kind of describes are vm and the other pieces that we need so
...to do is I'm now going to add a new resource and
you'll see here these are those things that I kind of I didn't want to say snippets
...kind of like snippets of json you could include into your json file and we have a
lot of common json snippets here if you want to put in availability set or a
another public ip address or maybe address
...solution but in our case we want
as sql database so let's go ahead and add a sequel database...this call it.
Where we...here...called the jeep sequel?
Database.
Now if I had a server that was already described
...json file I can pick that server and that's where the database
will be created or if not I can create a new one cyclic create new and now
...to the sequel server...called this are jeep sequel server.
Click ad so that's added the
jeeps sequel server to my json you actually see over here on the left in the json
outline you'll see that that's already been added so now I just have to click
...again to add that database now
...make...little bigger and you'll see that here that database was added.
If we click on this you'll see the here's where the sequel server was added
and in fact we also just automatically because we thought well you're probably going to want to
open up some of those ip ports on your server so
we included a firewall rule so you can open up any ip ports we didn't actually specify
any ip is but this is where you go in and maybe open ruptured deb box or something like that.
again, this is a great way to...so now that I've done that I want to deploy these
resources so there's a lot of parameters...go ahead and look you'll see all these bold
ones...the sequel server in the database there were additional parameters
that required so you'll see the...parameters are the ones that were added while I was doing this.
So, now we need to go to r parameter file.
One mouse...and
you'll see here's the parameter file that would give you by default but there's a bunch more parameters...to
...values so I can do that jasonkeath I love json I can do that and we give you
...and stuff that can help you but to be honest when you're setting the parameters I find a lot easier
just come here and do deploy and
when you do that brings up the deployment dialogue so here is where you can specify the
subscription the as your subscription you want to deployed...
And, then here's the resource group so all of these resources when we deploy these are all the get
deploy two-one resource group research group is a new first-class concept in the new as
your rm world of you
...to the portal every resource that gets created now always goes into one and
only one resource group it's great for gathering all your resources for an
app into one location are into one kind of container
a you can do management on that container
...you can easily destroy all of the resources in that resource group just by doing the research group
you can eventually you'll be able to do core management on that resource group as well as set
...back permission rule-based, rule-based access permissions which you can do today already
so resource groups real key...one.
And, we'll call this the...this call this the jeep.
...group movies...may have...call to just in case.
...what we'll do.
We'll use jeep...are suffix for all of our stuff.
And, then I pick a location for that resource group even though it's just a container it
still exists somewhere and it has certain functionality so actually is a...itself that
...somewhere so...create that real quick and now we with
a template the template and the parameter files already default...you can see so
there's a parameter if I had three or four different parameter files and for
the first one was a template if I had three four different parameter files from
a different environments this is where I could pick the different file when I go to deploy.
But, what you want what I like to do is a...edit here you'll see...nice a
nice dialogue that comes up and it shows you all of the parameters and for the parameters that you haven't
specified a value this is where you can go in and plug-in value?
So, let's go ahead and use...jeep to suffix.
But, I've learned my lesson there's a few these resources that don't like upper case characters
someone sept upper case some don't so I've just learned my lesson especially in demos...try to get
right the first-time to go ahead and go with all lower-case so this is...storage count.
This ...name this is the admin name for vm because remember...up
of gm as well as a sequel server...database...give this...add the name and a password.
You'll notice how it doesn't show me the characters there if we were to go look
at the parameter file you'd notice that this parameter with specified as a
secure string versus just a string and that's what tells the tools to
obfuscate one's been typed in and actually if I don't
click the save password button here it's not even a save that to the file but,
I will...click the same password.
And, that since you may end up see...all use a pass for that I never...
All right and then for a public ip will is do...to.
Public ip this is something you do once because once you've done this once will
stored in that parameter file and then you can just execute this easily over and over without
...the specify these.
And, I'll just...through these...
Server named again and get yourself in trouble.
And, we...a locations so we're working on making this a drop down there's
some technical details butfollow this pattern for now west us east
us those kind of those kind of names for your locations again when you that.
And, then we need.
And, how many more we got jeep to database...
All right so now we have all of our passwords and all over values
...hit save passwords.
And, save that now at this point
...at this point you can see that all my passwords are plugged
...all my parameter values are plugged in
...have to do that again I can do I can do this one of two ways I think most
...the time when you're getting started with this you're going to come to this dialog
...parameters like I just did and then you hit the deployed button.
It's not let up right this minute because I have to pick.
Indicate...the nine create a sheep...resource group what we call
Wrong...up wrong subscription
...in line we call the jeeps up there we go to resource group so again I
hit deployed here it was start deploying these resources but,
what I want to show you the new integration that we have with the our shell so in the to
dot five release so the for the few people that were using the point resource group before?
We didn't give you a choice we gave you a we gave you a
powerful file but it was not tied to this deployment dialogue so now this deployment
dialogue actually fires off the partial file that we supply you which is really cool because you can go on
and insert whatever else you want it also comes with a little danger because
you could break that powerful file and it could fail but don't do that.
So, if we open up our partial file first thing I want to point out is we have great
...a shun there there's a extension out there for our
shel how many people using the powerful extension many people okay so address
schools mvp he created a great extension
...open-source project we've invested a lot of time with adam and other people
in community and...a lot of work to groove give great colors asia and
in teller sensewe let...set break point so I can go in here right here and
celebrate point in here and hit f five basically run the script so
we give you all of that all of that rich editing of our shall...inside of visual studio so you don't have the jump out to
...you if you don't want to is still of icy we
...so just give me options like I said this is customizable so I could come here and do
...right dashing...you'll see the intelligence we...I could do a write this output?
Review something michael build from.
Our shell and vs and save that so you could have just hit
deploying the dialogue so don't get overwhelm that's all you want to do anand our...
ignore this part of the demo but for those of you that do use our shell maybe one
uses our...filed automated in the future...just want to show you that you can edit in debug this right
...of visual studio and then you take it put it in as part of your ci your
...integration or...is deployment so we have a break point
...now that's going to come here...say executed script.
And,...cancel xone scroll up some it cancel ignore
...messages you're going to see that there's a parameter here that has to be...in
normally are dialogue would...in that's white prompts me for that resource group location if
...we could we could fix that just by typing in west us there but we
won't you also see that we've hard coded this to use as
...resource group and really what we should reviews does anybody remember research group and
cheap to research group, come on, someone how we are.
...to research group let's go ahead and fill that in.
Thank you for whoever's...there.
All right so now we have a...name now we're going to run that again and also this right click here to
...script.
And, there so there's...for we want that resource group because again our dialogue would normally
pass that in will do west us.
And, there...that...break point so here we are right is that visual studio will break point
we're debugging our show which your partial person
...clapping now services no...people that's fine don't clap no pretty
...remember that the when I evaluate you guys.
...trying...right so I'm go ahead...here and,
you'll see if I make this output windows little bigger you actually see there's my code so
that obviously that writing output could be any code that you guys need anywhere you want will just keep
...here which is pretty cool and we'll get down here pretty quickly to the main saying so
this is the main here's the main method or the main command that matters this is going to
say hey actually deploy that resource group those first lines of code we're looking for things that we might need
upload into storage in the audio...is going to actually tear
apart that resource the json file and the parameter file is
going to...and go ahead and supply the parameter values
it's also going to look for any missing parameter values so let's say I didn't save my passwords which actually
is a best practice by the way they're using continuous integration you don't want to savior passwords
in the file but I did just for ease of demo here but if I wouldn't have right here
...prompted me for those passwords but because I did I can just take continue.
And, we will look...the output window here.
Not that one let's look at the output window.
And, we'll see that deployment is starting up first goes out
...validates that template and then it's going to go through resource by resource and actually talked to
the to the back-end and get all of those resources but up and it's going to do this
you'll see if we wait long enough here is actually to do this and spin up as many resources at a time
that can sort of figure out the dependencies but everything...try to put doing
parallel so it's pretty smart and pretty fast I bet you in three or four minutes of
gm a database and everything spun up and working I actually pre created one that
looks very similar to slightly different name you sign on to the portal.
Here at microsoft we have to factor off so I have to actually use my virtual smart
...just type that in.
That's probably because I have no limits on my as your...so I don't know.
Let's see here if we go I have this I created rather than a jeep
...finance app resources so define of the same way I just didn't want us to have
decision wait if I look at that you'll see that we have a vm
...or network interface card...public ip universal network...we have...
sequel database and the storage...the storage counts needed for that vm to store stuff
and storage if you're one or the server is if you click on the database will
actually tell you someone until you can do it.
Into tell you where the server is a...out these essentials here.
We can see where the...there
too so really easy to spin up resources what's great about this is with a couple
clicks like if I was maybe it's friday I'm done with this resource group
for the weekend I don't want to run all we can just come here and click delete
this destroy that whole resource group and all of resources underneath it
...just do one or two powerful commands and wipe of the whole resource group common in
monday go back on monday and I can just read...this and within minutes
have my research group and all those...not that I don't want you to keep given...money over the weekend but I'm just
give you an example of how you might be able take advantage of this.
Probably get...level.
So, such as cloud services yes those are not supported quite
yet I believe I believe they will be soon I don't know for sure
that's honest truth we just we now have...because we've been missing
ios support or vm support until just yesterday so,
I can't give you an exact date if you want to ping me and I can try to get more information on
mike dot morton microsoft-dot-com feel free some
...all dig the best I can but some things are just not publication...
So, that's still running it should be done any minute we're not going to wait for the
...with for so that's our as your resource manager
truly with that outline window get richer with that outline windowed makes it
so much easier...nice starting point use that outline
...navigate use that outline...extra chunks of json.
It's a little bit more work and go into the portal...click to
settles resources up but once you do a once with the json it's so easy to spin it
up it's like I don't have to...a second copy I don't remember the fifty
clicks that I went up and did on the portal...that seem json with different set
of parameter files looks like a little bit of work trust me you're...set something up more than
once take a look at the json files because it's going to save time long-run...one question here?
Sari not...about the research group opposes.
All of the billing...can you get
...invoice for resource group I believe up on the portal you
If you can't today you will be able to let me go here so here's that resource group,
yeah, so,
there's the...so this will show you the building for that all the resources in that resource group
again eventually we'll do core management so-if you
want-to say I'm not sure how granular it's going to get but you'll be able to specify how many things can be
created a resource group and because I can
assign role based access control I can say...pick on...this
is good-looking guy here in the beard has access to one resource group the finance one and this
guy who happens of beard also has access to the jeep resource group and that's
only two that's all you can use within my subscriptions you can't go party on my subscription
but you can do whatever you want those resource groups and then when I have core management that's coming in the future
...be able to go so big...that resource groups are
really gives you a lot of people today we see them generate a bunch of like
creating four five six subscriptions because that's the only way that you can control costs
are track costs so this helps of...so definitely look at resource groups?
All right let's go back and
...one last slide it's my time like eleven minutes...
...that doctor tooling so last demo how many folks are using
doctor zero there one there a couple?
Okay, I didn't use document be honest current use
darker until last week when my boss me to do.
So, I was like okay I know...go...thing on a...look at no not
really I my body shows are tools literally less than an hour.
And, I'm how a huge doctor fan so those folks
...leaving they're not doctor fans obviously olmsted.
But, I was I didn't...I didn't see the appeal of it at first but now it's like holy
...ar tools...so easy and the how fast you can spin up one of these
darker containers which I'll do my best to describe I've really been impressed honestly I'm
a I'm a convertso, there's this tooling is not built indoor
sdk it's actually a separatekind of in preview separate installed you just got the
...gallery I will say this is one of those tools are only works on
...twenty fifteen so install twenty fifteen rc you know,
put...of gm the svm up in as...that if you have an msdn subscription you can spin up and
user credit so how are you want install darker extension and play with it
it's pretty cool what these doctor images do or the darker containers
...they are separate concepts all talk about those little bit the
images kind of the description of what you want this container look like the
containers the instance the image is kind of like
the class if you think about it like object-oriented so the images the
...multiple instances of that doctor image it's really great because I can hand you a
doctor imager you doctor image and it's going to run just like it ran online that...images in a
full vm it's just a subset of the dependencies that you need
and your application code and are tools make it super easy to do so let's actually
the switch over all show you are tools...some great videos
...going even more depth which is where I learned a lot about this and I
would really suggest try it out right now we support linux gm's and only the
...dot net five the new sp dot net stuff but
my guess without committing anything is you'll see us have a lot more support as time goes?
So, let's real quick...we are running...time should work
...that unless a new project and here I'm going to go...dot net again and
...go ahead and call this the ...
Build demo...have been longer right.
All right so again as of right now we support just the
...dot net five website or actually you can also spin up
a command line project also in there so we're going to pick website.
Now if you...at the keynote you saw a quick version of them deploying to a
doctor image what I want to show you is how we created that linux machine with that
talker extension so on linux machining...darker extension it's going to help
you the communication it's going to generate a bunch of certificates for your get your environmental
...at first I was like...like a lot of work that we make it super easy
...I'll show you that so here we have an...dot net five project.
Let's just go to the just so we...go to the about screen.
...just put something in here.
Keyboards not
...so we'll just do something like hello from.
Build.
And, beards.
So,...he no I couldn't have done...
So, we'll do that and then we'll just go up and we will
published this article publish now the first-time some
...this new option you can see here we have this new option to do
darker containers so we're going to choose that.
...hidden click...containers now I do have three or four that I've created
ahead of time and all actually deployed of that so we don't have to wait but before deployed...
mike stocker vm I want to show...created that so I...here to new and all I did was
plug-in the name mike stocker.
Vm I chose the images I wanted...and like
I said today just today we support these...to images
of my guesses this is going to this is going to increase as, you know,
we've announced windows, windows doctor container so I would imagine...will support those
two you can choose the size you want again, I need to put in a server name and a password.
I'm not going to...because I'm not going to click okay here and what I want to show
you is the first-time I came in here I took a picture of it actually just
to show you this is what this is what that dialogue look like the first-time that
I deployed so it's got my name the name of the doctor image or the vm and you'll see
that's got to serve report that support that this machine here running the
doctor client is going to talk to the doctor machine or the doctor back-end they call
a doctor damon and we're going to send commands between their
on that port and you'll see that these certificates down here these aren't filled in we have the
auto generate this is were a whole bunch of magic happens that doctor extension gets installed
...the linux machine generates always certificates brings
...down the client allows you do secure communications between the doctor client here
and my doctor linux server up in the client up in the cloud so I'm going to go back to
...this one to show you what would look like
that first-time I'm not going to click okay here actually I will...
Just for fun.
...you...online tear off the call this probably like five
...as a few times and I'm not going to other generate and use the same certificates that
I have already and that's not lighten up because I need
...location...us okay when kicked off
so message pretty much says hey we're in a creative...for you put the extensions on it come back
and a few minutes and you'll see down here that we're doing exactly that the messages or role now so let's
say we wait maybe seven eight minutes takes two or three minutes to
...up linux machine takes three or four minutes to apply the
...generate the certificates seven minutes goes by I come back here
and I say okay now I want to publish my web app
to that linux gm with the extension that I just created so come through here.
...to pick this one but in like two or three minutes you're going to cv
...five...this list but this one I have is up...exact same thing I did
...okay and you can see all is a saying hey talk tcp to this guy here.
And, this is the image name that we're going to use the doctor file the
doctor file describes what that images going to be made up of you don't need to supply one
goes will audio generate one that basically just has a
...dot net and your application on it so we'll do the
basic if you want to customize one you can...customize at all you want.
As well you can customize the advanced communication options here which by the way I'm going to grab
...those in just a second I'm...grab that because that's how we talk again from the client
to the server and I'm going to validate the connection so this is just
saying the darker client can talk to that server and I'm going to publish and at times google,
google.
So, you'll see ...building this asp dot net five application
we're going out and resolving a bunch of the new get packages we're going to build that
the output libraries and then we're going to start talking to doctor over that port and
...not only application but a few other various things
we're going to send a couple commands that we want to build and image remember the images like the class and then
will spin up a container from that image which is like the instance of a class?
hopefully that will and momentarily and...website will be deployed in this
darker image up on this vm and I can split up a ton of these little
lightweight doctor images on that one vm super-fast bottom-up super-fast
the term down they're all in a mostly isolated environment and,
then we're in a launched...website and there we are in our doctor vm.
Were up there run that website...vm...dot net approve that...
will connect to that linux...just open up a plano command prompt and remember that
connections during that I copied this can...pace that in...say...run...and then use
and tls security protocol and...to the doctor vm and then...run a
...command which is ps to see the running
this shows you what the running containers so
that's the container we just spun up you can see that because it's been run for about a minute and that is
are application that's the web app that you saw when we went to
the url I can also look at the images so I do a similar
command remember the images or like the class
...the container is the instance relevant my images you'll see actually
to images the reason for that is my image which is this one if you looked at the
...file it had a dependency
and said start from a base image which is called this so the first-time
I deployed it actually took about four or five minutes because it had to copy down
...the...their.
...copy down eight hundred-fifty megs from doctor hub one-time because it
...that base image admitted applied my application and
...dependencies on top of that and built another image and each images
independence so the you don't go and you don't update images you create new images but once you have that
base images really fast as you saw it took maybe a minute minute-and-a-half tops.
You can stop those images you can stardom...again I could go on
a publicist second image up there it's really powerful I'm really I'm really get excited about this
dockers stuff and...suggest given to try and see...fits for your environment.
All right with that we're down to about a minute.
And, we have we have we did that all right so just
...wrap-up have some resources here I won't change...this.
Excuse me there were a couple sessions are of refer to that actually happened before hand so
I noted the recordings that you might...go what watch one was getting really even deeper into
diagnostics philosophy relieve and if you give a review of I'd appreciate it sir ones you
...sort...evaluation or review and appreciate but,
take a look at some of these classes the as your there's one more coming up tomorrow or
the top on there for as your api apps some might be something if you're
...in that new app service stuff we didn't get a chance to show you
the connected services I didn't want to show you that there was one of the thing I wanted...points
...leave this up and we have heard how many people have more than one
e-mail account that they sign in the measure...
...probably all of you have multiple subscriptions I want to show you
...make sure that everyone's aware of and here this is
envious twenty fifteen where we support multiple accounts envious
thirteen twenty thirteen we still support a flavor of this but, does everyone...
that you can come here and right click on the measure node that's my fault that wasn't of screen fault
...do it again so here we are the agile node right click managing
filter subscriptions...not aware that this can be really handy because if
you have multiple accounts in...twenty fifteen you can sign on with
multiple accounts now but even if you have a single account you got a bunch of subscriptions
you can filter so I can say well maybe I only want my work account
...live account and now you'll see the subscriptions went down
...them here and filter out my...subscriptions I...see that I
...go down to the region and only find resources flat region so for not familiar with this I just
want-to make...that people know-how to get to...can really be handy?
Especially envious twenty fifteen we support multiple accounts.
And, with that
all wrap-up...hang around take any questions afterwards thanks-a-lot hopefully hopefully
helped you find a good nugget that you can go and use install address
...to six install...twenty fifteen rc at least give it a
try I think you'll like a lot of the cool things we've done there thanks...evaluation.